

Serhii Mykhailov

DevOps Engineer

mail@mykhailov.pp.ua

linkedin.com/in/s-mykhailov t.me/mykhailov_s github.com/Mihailov-SA mynote.pp.ua fb.com/mykhailov.s/

About me:

Rised up from dungeon SysAdmin to DevOps.

10+ years of experience as a System Administrator: huge background in server infrastructure/datacenter operations management, strong Windows/Linux, Networking knowledges.

2+ years as a DevOps with experience in: IaC, CaC, CI/CD and almost all AWS cloud features.

Results and customer-oriented. Good in communication, problem localization and solving, critical and open-minded, self-motivated and self-management, ability to self-education. Absolutely cold-blooded, clean and methodical in critical issue solving.

My motto: anything that needs to be repeated more than 2 times should be automated.

my work == my hobby.

Experience:

Automat-IT (DevOps company)

Role: DevOps Engineer, Jan 2021 - present

A lot of projects and customers. Setup and support a new and existing insfra in the cloud. All major cloud providers, but mostly AWS.

CICD: Jenkins, GitHub Actions, AWS CodePipeline | CodeBuild.

IaC: Terraform, Pulumi, CloudFormation.

CaC: Ansible, AWS SSM.

Scripting: Bash, Python, Groovy, SQL.

Monitoring: Cloudwatch, NewRelic, Zabbix, Grafana, Datadog.

Knowledge of all major AWS tools and services such as: EC2, Lambda, ECS, S3, EBS, RDS, ELB, Route53, CloudFront, CloudWatch, etc. Experience with Hybrid env's (VMware ESXi + aws).

LIDER-TREYD LTD (logistics)

Role: System Administrator, 2015 - 2021

Setup and support hypervisors based on Hyper-V; Citrix XEN;

Windows 2008-2016: AD; GPO; DNS; DHCP; IIS; RDP/remote-app; MSSQL; 1C 7-8.2; SEP controller;

Debian based: mysql; apache; owncloud; samba; pbisopen; vsftpd; jabber; motion; docker; zabbix; traccar.

Networking: Mikrotik; Zywall; Draytek; Ubiquiti, HP procurve. Firewall; DHCP; DNS; NAT; openvpn; IPsec; site-to-site VPN; Load-Balancing; WiFi-roaming;

Support users workstations based on Windows XP-10. Selection of components and assembly of bare metal servers. Configuration backups, replications (master-slave), helpdesk services and monitoring. Bash; powershell; python; RouterOS scripting. Cloud providers: DigitalOcean.

Epicall (call centre)

Role: System Administrator, 2014 - 2015

XenServer v6.5 hypervisor. CentOS based VMs. Configuring tunnels for customers servers. Support users workstations based on Ubuntu. Setting up the company's internal LAN and WiFi.

DVBTD (brokerage company)

Role: System Administrator, 2010 - 2014

Debian-based server: LAMP; SAMBA; FTP; OpenVPN; CUPS. Support workstations based on Windows XP-7. Configuring and support company's website, LAN, WiFi.

Education and certification details:

Udemy | AWS SysOps Administrator

2022, AWS SOA-C02 Exam

Certification was successful.

Cert Validation Number: ZXL4JNGCTBB1QH9V.

Udemy | AWS Cloud Practitioner

2021, AWS CLF-C01 exam

Certification was successful.

Cert Validation Number: JV2Z3P2DD1411QS0.

DevOps course Zone3000

2020, DevOps Basics

Successfully completed the course and received a certificate.

Donetsk National University of Economics and Trade

2010 - 2014, Maste

Mechanical engineering

Skills summary:

Operating Systems | Hypervisors | Container runtimes:

Linux: Debian, Alpine, Ubuntu, CenOS, Amazon Linux.

Windows: 7-10, Server 2003-2019

Hyper-V, Proxmox, VMware ESXi, XEN, LXC, Docker

IAAC | CAAC:

Terraform, Pulumi, CloudFormation, Ansible, AWS SSM

CI/CD tools:

Jenkins, CodeBuild/CodePipeline, GitHub Actions

Scripting:

Bash, Python, PowerShell, Groovy, SQL

DB Engines (administration level):

MySQL, MSSQL, RDS Aurora

Hardware:

Mikrotik, Ubiquiti, Zyxel Zywall, Draytek, HP ProCurve, HP proliant, Supermicro.

Experience in selecting components and assembling bare-metal servers

Language:

English - Pre Intermediate Ukrainian - Native Russian - Native

Last updated at 01/02/2023 by GitHub Actions